Jekyll2020-09-15T09:21:46+03:00https://mpc-hc.org/rss.xmlMPC-HCMPC-HC, the free, open source media player for Windowsv1.7.13 is released and farewell2017-07-16T19:00:00+03:002017-07-16T19:00:00+03:00https://mpc-hc.org/2017/07/16/1.7.13-released-and-farewell<p>v1.7.13, the latest, and probably the <em>last</em> release of our project…</p> <p>For quite a few months now, or even years, the number of active developers has been decreasing and has inevitably reached zero. This, unfortunately, means that the project is officially dead and this release would be the last one.</p> <p>…<em>Unless</em> some people step up that is.</p> <p>So, if someone’s willing to really contribute and <strong>has C/C++ experience</strong>, let me know on IRC or via e-mail.</p> <p>Otherwise, all things come to an end and life goes on. It’s been a nice journey and I’m personally pretty overwhelmed having to write this post.</p> <p>Thanks to everyone who has contributed in any way all these years; Remember, MPC-HC is an 11-year old project.</p> <hr /> <p>Don’t forget, that our official builds, both the stable and the beta builds, <a href="/2013/02/25/binaries-are-signed/">are digitally signed</a>. Be aware of scams and only get the files from our site!</p> <p>Also, to report bugs, suggestions and generally provide feedback, use our <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/">Trac</a>; reporting anything on social media or in any other place is just pointless, as the developers only follow Trac.</p> <p>You can download the new version <a href="/downloads/">here</a>. For the complete changes see the <a href="/changelog/">changelog</a>.</p>XhmikosRv1.7.13, the latest, and probably the last release of our project…v1.7.11 is released2017-03-06T16:00:00+02:002017-03-06T16:00:00+02:00https://mpc-hc.org/2017/03/06/1.7.11-released<p>After <em>a long time</em> since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.11.</p> <p>A few highlights of this release:</p> <ul> <li>Add support for Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) as a toolbar image. Make the default toolbar image DPI-aware, therefore make the interface more friendly for high DPI monitors.</li> <li>Brand new, rewritten subtitle downloading framework including the following features: <ul> <li>Support for multiple subtitle providers including the default OpenSubtitles as well as podnapisi, titlovi, SubDB, ysubs and Napisy24 which can be enabled in Options (Subtitles → Misc)</li> <li>Ability to upload subtitles to OpenSubtitles and SubDB</li> <li>Ability to login into OpenSubtitles</li> <li>Ability to filter subtitle list by selected languages</li> <li>Option to automatically search and download subtitles at the beginning of playback without user interaction</li> <li>Prioritize subtitles for hearing impaired where indicated</li> </ul> </li> <li>Add shader cache to speed up playback start with complex shader chains</li> <li>Add the ability to set audio delay depending on the screen resolution</li> <li>Remove old deprecated DirectX 7 renderers. Settings will be updated automatically to use the corresponding VMR-9 renderers. If you really want to use a renderer similar to VMR-7 (windowed), use Overlay mixer or the “System Default” renderer.</li> <li>Change Pan&amp;Scan logic to be able to quickly rotate video <ul> <li>PnS Rotate Y- now flips horizontally</li> <li>PnS Rotate X- now flips vertically</li> <li>PnS Rotate Z- now rotates 90 degrees (counter-clockwise)</li> </ul> </li> <li>New Bosnian translation. Remember that you can <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/wiki/Translations">help us</a> translating MPC-HC to your language.</li> </ul> <p>Don’t forget, that our official builds, both the stable and the beta builds, <a href="/2013/02/25/binaries-are-signed/">are digitally signed</a>. Be aware of scams and only get the files from our site!</p> <p>Also, to report bugs, suggestions and generally provide feedback, use our <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/">Trac</a>; reporting anything on social media or in any other place is just pointless, as the developers only follow Trac.</p> <p>You can download the new version <a href="/downloads/">here</a>. For the complete changes see the <a href="/changelog/">changelog</a>.</p> <h2 id="mpc-hc-status-and-the-future">MPC-HC status and the future</h2> <p>As you may have noticed there was not much traction in the MPC-HC project in the recent months. We do apologize if you felt bad about that. Unfortunately, we were not able to provide as much development time as MPC-HC deserves. We believe MPC-HC is a very capable player and we want to keep it rocking for much more years to come. Sadly, currently, we don’t really have the manpower to do so. But this does not mean we want to give up here. We consider this release as a new starting point and hopefully, we will slowly but steadily improve MPC-HC.</p> <p>If you care about MPC-HC’s future, please contact us. Report issues that you want to be worked on and most importantly send patches if you can; even small changes help us move forward.</p>XhmikosRAfter a long time since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.11.v1.7.10 is released2015-11-14T19:00:00+02:002015-11-14T19:00:00+02:00https://mpc-hc.org/2015/11/14/1.7.10-released<p>After 5 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.10.</p> <p>This release is a bugfix release, with many improvements and a few new features.</p> <p>A few highlights of this release:</p> <ul> <li>Completely new Internal Audio Renderer: <ul> <li>Uses sanear project as backend</li> <li>Requires Windows Vista or newer</li> <li>Outputs sound through WASAPI (shared or exclusive)</li> <li>Employs automatic channel downmixing</li> <li>Provides stereo crossfeed processing option (for headphones)</li> <li>Tries to preserve signal pitch when playing at custom rate (time stretching)</li> <li>Supports bitstreaming</li> </ul> <p>Note that you need to select the new renderer in options in order to use it</p> </li> <li>Windows 10 related fixes: <ul> <li>Improved mouse behavior</li> <li>Fixed volume control with scroll wheel</li> <li>Window snapping to desktop edges</li> </ul> </li> <li>Allow hardware decoding of UHD video with AMD cards</li> <li>Big video rendering stability improvement</li> <li>New Indonesian, Lithuanian and Punjabi translations. Remember that you can <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/wiki/Translations">help us</a> translating MPC-HC to your language.</li> </ul> <p>Don’t forget, that our official builds, both the stable and the beta builds, <a href="/2013/02/25/binaries-are-signed/">are digitally signed</a>. Be aware of scams and only get the files from our site!</p> <p>Also, to report bugs, suggestions and generally provide feedback, use our <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/">Trac</a>; reporting anything on social media or in any other place is just pointless, as the developers only follow Trac.</p> <p>You can download the new version <a href="/downloads/">here</a>. For the complete changes see the <a href="/changelog/">changelog</a>.</p>XhmikosRAfter 5 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.10.Binaries moved to MaxCDN2015-06-21T00:00:00+03:002015-06-21T00:00:00+03:00https://mpc-hc.org/2015/06/21/binaries-hosting-switch<p>In the light of recent events, we decided to move away from SourceForge completely.</p> <p>SourceForge has served us well for many years, from the very first days back in 2006. But many things have changed since then, and we needed to adapt to that.</p> <p>First, <a href="/2012/08/09/source-code-moved-to-github/">we moved our source code to GitHub</a>. Then we managed to <a href="/2013/02/24/website-was-moved/">move to our own server and domain</a>, the server was kindly provided by <a href="https://www.cloudvps.com/">CloudVPS</a>.</p> <p>Now the time has come to move the last thing away from SourceForge, which is our binaries. We are happy to be provided with a CDN by <a href="https://www.maxcdn.com/">MaxCDN</a>. Right now everything on this site is powered by MaxCDN infrastructure, including the binaries.</p> <p>What does this mean for our end users, you? Speed should be a lot better for people around the world. Should any issues arise, feel free to <a href="/contact-us/">contact us</a>.</p>XhmikosRIn the light of recent events, we decided to move away from SourceForge completely.v1.7.9 is released2015-06-01T00:00:00+03:002015-06-01T00:00:00+03:00https://mpc-hc.org/2015/06/01/1.7.9-released<p>After 4 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.9.</p> <p>This release is a bugfix release, with many improvements and a few new features.</p> <p>A few highlights of this release:</p> <ul> <li>DVB HEVC support</li> <li>DTS Music Disc support</li> <li>Fixed subtitle color conversion issues</li> <li>Improved Playlist shuffle mode</li> <li>New <a href="/crash-reporter/">crash handler</a>. Many thanks to the DrDump developer for all his help and cooperation!</li> <li>New Danish translation. Remember that you can <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/wiki/Translations">help us</a> translating MPC-HC to your language.</li> </ul> <p>Don’t forget, that our official builds, both the stable and the beta builds, <a href="/2013/02/25/binaries-are-signed/">are digitally signed</a>. Be aware of scams and only get the files from our site!</p> <p>Also, to report bugs, suggestions and generally provide feedback, use our <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/">Trac</a>; reporting anything on social media or in any other place is just pointless, as the developers only follow Trac.</p> <p>You can download the new version <a href="/downloads/">here</a>. For the complete changes see the <a href="/changelog/">changelog</a>.</p>XhmikosRAfter 4 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.9.Issues downloading MPC-HC2015-03-03T00:00:00+02:002015-03-03T00:00:00+02:00https://mpc-hc.org/2015/03/03/issues-downloading-mpc-hc<p>It has come to our attention that some people are having trouble downloading MPC-HC.</p> <p>See the related Google <a href="https://search.googleblog.com/2015/02/more-protection-from-unwanted-software.html">blog post</a>.</p> <p>As a result of those changes to the malware protection in Google Chrome, SourceForge, which is hosting our MPC-HC downloads, can’t be used to get the latest version of our software. We advise users to use a different browser like <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/">Mozilla Firefox</a> or disable the malware protection in Chrome in order to download MPC-HC.</p>XhmikosRIt has come to our attention that some people are having trouble downloading MPC-HC.v1.7.8 is released2015-01-25T00:00:00+02:002015-01-25T00:00:00+02:00https://mpc-hc.org/2015/01/25/1.7.8-released<p>After 3 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.8.</p> <p>This release is a bugfix release, with many improvements and a few new features.</p> <p>Highlights of this release:</p> <ul> <li>Improved DVB playback mode and compatibility</li> <li>Support RTMP streams with librtmp style parameters</li> <li>Many stability fixes (subtitles, renderers, etc)</li> <li>New Finnish and Serbian translations. Remember that you can <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/wiki/Translations">help us</a> translating MPC-HC to your language.</li> </ul> <p>Don’t forget, that our official builds, both the stable and the beta builds, <a href="/2013/02/25/binaries-are-signed/">are digitally signed</a>. Be aware of scams and only get the files from our site!</p> <p>Also, to report bugs, suggestions and generally provide feedback, use our <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/">Trac</a>; reporting anything on social media or in any other place is just pointless, as the developers only follow Trac.</p> <p>You can download the new version <a href="/downloads/">here</a>. For the complete changes see the <a href="/changelog/">changelog</a>.</p>XhmikosRAfter 3 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.8.SourceForge Project of the Month results2014-11-14T00:00:00+02:002014-11-14T00:00:00+02:00https://mpc-hc.org/2014/11/14/november-sf-project-of-the-month-results<p>Thanks to all of our users who voted for us, we are SourceForge’s Project of the Month for November!</p> <p>Feel free to check the related <a href="https://sourceforge.net/blog/november-2014-community-choice-project-of-the-month-mpc-hc/">blog post</a>, accompanied with a small “interview”.</p> <p>Thanks everyone for their support! It gives us all strength to keep going!</p> <p>P.S. Yeah, it’s almost half of the month already, but you know, Real Life™.</p>XhmikosRThanks to all of our users who voted for us, we are SourceForge’s Project of the Month for November!v1.7.7 is released2014-10-05T00:00:00+03:002014-10-05T00:00:00+03:00https://mpc-hc.org/2014/10/05/1.7.7-released<p>After 3 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.7.</p> <p>This release is a bugfix release, with many improvements and a few new features.</p> <p>Highlights of this release:</p> <ul> <li>Fixed a crash affecting DVD playback with subtitles on 64-bit builds</li> <li>Worked around a bug in the latest NVIDIA driver (v344.11) which caused a corrupted display of 10-bit videos</li> <li>Improved HEVC decoding: software decoding should be up to twice faster and hardware accelerated decoding is now available (but still experimental so disabled by default)</li> <li>Improved subtitle renderer and subtitle queue (more than twice faster on complex subtitle scripts)</li> <li>Support for audio cover art</li> <li>New Arabic and Thai translations. Remember that you can <a href="https://trac.mpc-hc.org/wiki/Translations">help us</a> translating MPC-HC to your language.</li> </ul> <p>Don’t forget, that our official builds, both the stable and the beta builds, <a href="/2013/02/25/binaries-are-signed/">are digitally signed</a>. Be aware of scams and only get the files from our site!</p> <p>You can download the new version <a href="/downloads/">here</a>. For the complete changes see the <a href="/changelog/">changelog</a>.</p>XhmikosRAfter 3 months since our last stable build, we are happy to announce v1.7.7.SourceForge Project of the Month2014-09-26T00:00:00+03:002014-09-26T00:00:00+03:00https://mpc-hc.org/2014/09/26/november-sf-project-of-the-month-ballot<p>Our project has been selected for the ballot for November “Community Choice” Project of the Month.</p> <p>The vote is conducted on SourceForge and runs through <strong>Oct 15th</strong>.</p> <p>The blog post linking to this vote is <a href="https://sourceforge.net/blog/community-choice-project-of-the-month-vote-november/">here</a>, and the vote itself <a 
